<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Social Data Science</title>
    <link>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Social Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>sodas@ku.dk (Center for Social Data Science)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sodas@ku.dk (Center for Social Data Science)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exam project</title>
      <link>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sodas@ku.dk (Center for Social Data Science)</author>
      <guid>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/exam/</guid>
      <description>When the teaching in our course finishes you are to hand in a project. The formal requirements are found here along with details on grading. The exam period runs from August 23, 2019 from 15 PM to August 30 at 15 PM.
In this blog post we want to expand a little bit on how a good project will look. The focus of the project is to pose and interesting question to data that can be collected publicly and attempt to answer it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Jupyter tips</title>
      <link>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sodas@ku.dk (Center for Social Data Science)</author>
      <guid>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>This post provides a short intro on picking up useful Jupyter hacks. We begin with a short overview of the most essential Jupyter shortcuts and skills. If you have not read the introduction to Jupyter you should do that immediately, see here.
Keyboard short cuts Editing and executing cells - enter edit mode: click inside the cell or press ENTR - exit edit mode: click outside cell or press ESC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparation</title>
      <link>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sodas@ku.dk (Center for Social Data Science)</author>
      <guid>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/preparation/</guid>
      <description>Guide to preparations It is necessary that you time preparing for the course. We expect that you have spent 30-50 hours on learning basic Python before we begin teaching. In particular you should do the following (prioritized order):
 Install anaconda and other software Install nbgrader with anaconda (write pip install nbgrader in the terminal/prompt) Open Assignment 0 in Jupyter notebook, see this guide on how to open and use a notebook Work on Assignment 0 - try to solve as much as possible When you get stuck then follow the trouble shooting guidline below - start with a) and move to d) see material below for learning Python - make sure you have read all material about the relevant problem search on Google, in particular stackexchange is very useful ask other people, you may already now other Python experts open a GitHub issue in our SDS2019 repository  If you have extra time you can familiarize yourself with your operating system (OS), i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sodas@ku.dk (Center for Social Data Science)</author>
      <guid>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/install/</guid>
      <description>This class will involve a lot of coding, for which you will need some basic tools. Please make sure to set up the following tools before the first day of class.
 Python and Jupyter notebook A git client A github account A text editor  We will discuss these tools in much more detail in class, so don&amp;rsquo;t worry if this is all new and perhaps a bit frightening right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignments</title>
      <link>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>sodas@ku.dk (Center for Social Data Science)</author>
      <guid>https://abjer.github.io/sds2019/post/assignment/</guid>
      <description>This post contain practical information related to each of the three assignments. Check back later for news about deadlines and other assignment related information.
Assignment 0: Available July 15. Deadline August 11 @ 20.00
Assignment 1: Available August 15. Deadline August 18 @ 20.00
Assignment 2: Available August 21 at 12pm (noon). Deadline August 23 @ 15.00</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>